

# **MOHAMMED REFAEE**

(Software Engineer)

ADDRESS: UAE

MOBILE: +971 0582668752

EMAIL: m.refaee123580@gmail.com

Nationality: Syrian

## **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

I'm software engineer with strong academic background and I'm focusing on web development especially (Asp.net and angular) I seek challenging opportunities where I can fully use my skills for the success of the organization

I am Fluent in Arabic and English with 2 years employment Visa and work permit(NOC).

# **EDUCATION**

#### ALBAATH UNIVERSITY - Syria:

- Bachelor of IT engineering (5 years) specialist in: Software engineering with GPA 77 %
- Relevant Courses: ISO 27001 Information Security, Computer support

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### (DXB GUIDE, UAE, Dubai)

WordPress developer, Jan 2020 - Apr 2020:

- Develop databases that support web applications and web sites,
- Renew domain name registrations.
- Design, build, or maintain web sites, using authoring or scripting languages, content creation tools, management tools, and digital media,
- Design and maintain E-commerce websites using WooCommerce

#### (InClick, Syria, Damascus)

#### Web developer (Dotnet Framework and Angular), Jan 2017 - Jan 2020:

- Write, design, or edit web page content, or direct others producing content.
- Maintain understanding of current web technologies or programming practices through continuing education, reading, or participation in professional conferences, workshops, or groups.
- Develop databases that support web applications and web sites.
- Collaborate with management or users to develop e-commerce strategies and to integrate these strategies with web sites,
- Communicate with network personnel or web site hosting agencies to address hardware or software issues affecting web sites.

# (TECHNO GATE, Syria, Homs)

#### IT Helpdesk, Mar 2016 - May 2017:

- Maintain and administer computer networks and related computing environments including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Perform data backups and disaster recovery operations
- Diagnose, troubleshoot, and resolve hardware, software, or other network and system problems, and replace
  defective components when necessary.

### **LANGUAGES**

Arabic: NativeEnglish: Fluent

### HARD SKILLS

- .NET C# MVC ASP.net Core Azure visual studio backend developer
- frontend HTML CSS JavaScript Bootstrap
- JS framework typescript Angular 6+
- Java OOP C++ API Restful web services Entity framework LINO ADO
- ArcG1S management and SQL, SQL server
- Microsoft office, windows server, active directory and windows 7-8-10
- Laravel, blade, artisan, Heroku and google cloud console
- Mobile App development using flutter Framework and Dart
- Arabic- English Translation and teaching

### **SOFT SKILLS**

- Updating My Skills with UpToDate technologies
- Adaptability
- Agile processes
- Excellent communication skills
- Strong collaboration skills
- Teamwork
- Creative thinking
- Analytical thinking

### PROJECTS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

http://tareq.cloudaccess.host

Ecommerce Store on WordPress WooCommerce

http://gc2.online

Landing Page website for Chemical Company

## https://dating.azurewebsites.net/home

 $\mathbf{Dating}\ \mathbf{website}$  (Multi-tier) using Asp.net Core for backend and Angular 9 for frontend beside MySQL and entity Framework

http://memo94.herokuapp.com

Posting website with MEAN stack (NodeJS, Express, MongoDB and Angular)

http://memo94.000webhostapp.com/

My portfolio website

# https://mysport.azurewebsites.net/

E-commerce website (Multi-tier) using Asp.net Core for backend and Angular 9 for frontend beside SQL server and entity Framework

### **INTERESTS**

- Music
- History
- Geography
- Gaming